it's a good job that i did some reading
because i made
many many mistakes in this farm building
it turns out that although zombie
piglens will spawn here for my gold farm
in the crimson forest they don't spawn
very often and i also learnt that these
hoglands they don't like warped fungus
oh so many of my problems would have
been fixed by reading just reading a
small amount
and i would have saved myself a few
hours work because this is essentially a
dead space now so
i've wasted a lot of time but that's not
a problem because i found a new location
now where we need to build this is the
nether waste
and i also want to show you something so
obviously flying around the nether like
this
you can't see
anything it's actually quite annoying
you can't see much and i was like how am
i gonna find a new location
well in optifine
there is an option to turn the fog off
geez
look at this the nether is
completely different
in fact
i think that's a bastion over there
it looks 100
different and there are no particles
around i wish there was a middle ground
where there was just fog in the
background like really far away instead
of immediately in your face but it's
either all or nothing by the looks of
things we've got to go and check out
this bastion there is a big pile of gold
with my name on it wow and i think that
was in the shape of like a hoglin or
piglet because they look like they could
have been tusks i gotta say these
bastions are pretty cool oh my goodness
this is it is completely transformed
what the nether is like there is there
are still some particles around actually
it's just the fog is gone anyway what i
was looking for
was this the treasure rooms crying
obsidian i need that to make a respawn
anchor which i definitely need to do and
another one on the other side
oh my goodness and of course doing a
little bit more research and i mean
people were screaming at me in the
comments
you just gotta wear one bit of gold
armor
on your booties or on your head and
yeah the piglens don't attack you either
whoa
and a soul speed book so with this fog
gone i'm now able to locate a new place
and i think that i found one
unfortunately for me
i haven't come prepared again and i've
i'm out of rockets already
however i do believe that i have found
one just over here it's only like 200
blocks away
and there is a enormous nether fortress
around here so
not only do i have the nether waste
biome i've got a nice open area here
which i can do exactly the same thing my
upside down base
and it has more biomes for me to use so
i think this could be the place in which
case what we need to do is make our way
up here and change the coordinates
for the bedrock to be broken i'm
officially out of rockets as well
so we're gonna have to dig upwards and i
think i'm just gonna make i think i'm
gonna make a tunnel so that i can just
fly back really easily i'm so
unorganized so let's start mining all
the way back to my portal
i made it back to my base and i have
created the world's best unintentional
mob farm
that is
dangerous
really really dangerous
no no no no
look at that
absolute carnage anyway i have finished
the portal oh and the carnage the
carnage has been going through the
portal
the carnage has been going through the
no
so to get to my base all you're gonna do
is go straight past the spawn portal and
it is right
here
now this is a really really long tunnel
and you've got to keep flying all the
way if you stop you cannot start flying
again so you've really got to keep it up
and just to prove how long it is it
takes it takes a few minutes to just fly
through it
it just keeps going
and going
and going until eventually
we make it but the worst thing is i've
spent ages and you saw how oh
someone needs to make a compilation of
all the weird noises that i make now you
just saw how long that tunnel is and it
took a long time to dig out and then i
get back just to find out impulse has
done the job of breaking the bedrock i
can just fly over the top now the nether
project isn't going so well it's just a
series of frustrating events but
now we are fully kitted out i have got
rockets galore i have got my magma
blocks i've got everything i could
possibly need
all i have to do now is actually just
get started on this base my new location
is here in the nether wastes because
this is where you can make some good
farms there's the crimson forest there
and then there's also the nether
fortress which i'm sure i can do
something with
so without further ado
let's get some work done for real this
time let's make a functional
thing
so
let's
go
[Music]
i've come to realize that the nether's
not exactly easy
now i have started a few other projects
up here as you can see i've got some
soul sand and i am getting some
netherwart under the way this is for a
very good reason but first let's go and
have a look down at my farm i've created
a multi-layer magma farm now
here's a really embarrassing thing i
oh
didn't think about ghast
i didn't think about guests
this is like learn oh
[Music]
this is like learning minecraft all over
again this is really bad so several
embarrassing things have happened that
weren't just the ghasts so i didn't
actually count so my first design i put
only two spaces now if you have two
spaces between your magma layers the
pigment can't actually see the eggs so
they spawn in and they don't go anywhere
you have to put three in but then i
thought ah i'll be clever and what i'll
do is i'll i'll just move one of the
layers and one of them won't be as big
so this layer is correct this is three
high
but the one that you just saw above
i believe this is uh four blocks high as
far as i'm aware i think gas can spawn
in this particular layer because there's
space for them so i mean the fix for
this is very easy i just got to add a
layer under this no problem but it's
just mistake after mistake after mistake
for this build honestly it's getting
it's getting bad but i am getting to the
point where i am ready to start building
and you can see the rates of this
they're not fantastic like i know that
and i knew that when i decided to make
it here and not on the roof
i knew that the rates weren't going to
be great but the the pigment are
spawning and they are going to the
middle and i created a very temporary
collection solution down here with some
oh no
did you see that
that was a mid-air deflection
okay guards are the most annoying thing
so i've created a very temporary
collection system and it's well it's as
you can see it's doing pretty good and
this will all get crafted up into gold
bars for a future piglet farm but now
that i've got this i'm now ready to
start no
bad
this is why people don't settle in the
nether but i'm i'm determined now
so i've created the farm that was the
first thing this actually dictates how
big my base is going to be around it so
what i'm going to try and do now is
create the base hanging from the ceiling
now this means a few things
i need to i need to make a platform like
a really big platform down here because
as i'm building obviously blocks are
going to be falling and not only blocks
i'm going to be falling and i've already
fallen in the lava once
and i don't want it to happen again so
this spot here where all these zombie
pigmen keep spawning i need to get rid
of this and at the same time i need a
lot of netherrack so i'm killing two
birds with one stone now the reason i
need a lot of netherrack is because
i actually want to make my base or part
of the base color out of red nether
brick which needs two things one is
netherrack and two is never wart so
between the two
i can get enough resources to make lots
of red nether brick no one i don't think
anyone really builds with this block
it's fairly new it's not in this update
but
no one really builds with it i think
it's a pain to it's a bit of an odd
color for a start and it's a bit strange
as a building block as well it doesn't
really fit in but with this build it
will so i never thought i'd do this but
i need to make a mass nether wart farm
and i need a lot of netherrack
really weird combination of things that
i need in order to make this build the
blocks that i need are very strange but
for the most part i've got the other
stuff like the stone and the cyan
terracotta all that stuff so we need to
go into another time lapse now of
collecting the nether wall and
collecting all the netherrack to get
this job done which means expanding this
farm as big as possible
so let's give it a go
[Music]
everything was going okay until this
moment
honestly some of the weirdest things
i've ever said have come out of this
farm i had to tell my friend earlier
that i i had to get home because i had
to replenish my warts
and they said what i was like yeah i'm
growing some warts
obviously they didn't realize i was
talking about minecraft
and then i realized
yeah that's a pretty weird thing to say
isn't it so i have indeed replenished my
warts several times and i have grown a
fair amount of warts in fact i think
i've grown more warts in the history of
anyone who's super warty so the reason
that i have all of these warts is for
this exact reason i want to create this
block and i feel like no one ever makes
this block i've not really seen it used
in builds very much but i'm about to
change that red nether brick and the
great thing about this is they
introduced some staircases and some
slabs for this
so
this is going to be the roof block for
my nether build however i haven't
actually got enough not nearly enough
it's it's actually really expensive look
so this is
netherrack put into a furnace so that's
two stacks of netherrack two stacks of
warts and that gives you one stack of
red nether bricks so it's a very
expensive block which means i'm gonna
have to do a whole lot more farming and
i'm gonna have to set up a lot of
furnaces like so i would use my super
smelter but it's actually kind of far
away so now i have the task of
smelting netherrack
this is about as boring as it gets in
minecraft this is the minecraft
equivalent of watching paint dry
having to smelt netherrack and the great
thing is by removing big floating
islands like i did over there i actually
have a almost infinite supply of
netherrack so i can terrain and collect
resources at the same time the paint is
on we're watching it dry and it's slowly
going ahead at least it's starting to
feel like this area is a bit more
productive i know this isn't a super
smelter and i have one back at my base
but it would just take so long going
back and forth i honestly can't believe
i've spent hours doing this now however
now that i have
over a shulker box full of red nether
bricks it means i can get started on the
base finally now that the paint is still
drying i can get started so we've got to
hop down in here and let me briefly
explain what we're going to be building
so from here i'm going to cover up this
farm
and basically have an upside down
mansion it's still oh he's still
producing gold by the way i've actually
from just farming warts and stuff i've
actually got a fair amount of gold for
what i want to do afterwards now i'm
probably not going to have one enough
resources or two enough time to complete
the whole thing knowing what i want to
do but i should be able to get this
front portion here done
so
without further ado let's get into
another time lapse building and for that
i'm gonna need a giant platform so i am
not risking my items for this thing so
let's begin
[Music]
[Applause]
oh
boy found myself in a bit of a strange
situation
why does this why does this look the
most non-minecraft thing ever
so anyway as you saw from the time-lapse
the very lengthy time-lapse i might add
i have started my mansion upside down in
the nether
now i messed up quite a few things but
overall
not as much as a disaster as other
things
those things have been a tremendous
difficulty but i've managed as soon as i
hear them as soon as i hear that
i'm like gust and i go and i hunt them
down or they vanish on their own either
way
i'm pretty pleased with how this has
come out now i there is something i
definitely have to do which is
spawn proof it because this is actually
making my farm
not very efficient
so you can see it is an exact replica
of my mansion just upside down now that
is extremely difficult to build and i've
probably messed up quite a lot of things
but there's there's plenty of time to
fix it so instead of just the back not
being done it's gonna be most of it not
being done for a while i'm hoping i can
get side one side two done in an episode
each so surely this one and this is a
much much smaller version of my mansion
okay so this is like an exact replica of
the main bit the bit that i built first
however
look how small it is compared to the
nether this building just made the scary
nether
look teeny tiny it doesn't look like it
fits the nether okay look so i look
around wow look at that it looks oh wow
it's such a long drop it's massive
tiny
it's absolutely tiny and as such there's
not a huge gap between the bottom of the
ceiling that's really strange the
ceiling is at the bottom
and the lava i no the main thing that i
messed up was the distance i thought i
calculated how tall this was going to be
so i started here because of you really
do have to start from the bottom working
from up there downwards is just not
realistic for building oh they keep
falling down so i got it off by a few
blocks which is why i've had to dig into
the ceiling just a little bit to reveal
these bottom parts but on the whole not
bad
not bad at all just it's messing up my
farm drops now so what i'm thinking i'll
do next episode is maybe
make the other farm so
whatever other nether related farms i
want to make i'll make one here i'll
make one on the other side and then
build the mansion around it i think
that's the way to go here seeing as
that's what we've done with this one we
built this first and then we built the
mansion around it and it is weird that
they're just falling straight through
the mansion do you know what the ghasts
are okay you can deal with the gas it's
the blazes that are really quite an
issue in this
there is so much work to be done in this
part of the nether and it's actually
really really lonely being out here all
by myself isn't the most fun and
potentially i chose not the best
location to entice people but i'm
thinking i can i can invite some people
over here see if they want to form like
a nether colony over here something like
that i think that would be cool but this
has been an extraordinarily hard-working
episode not too much prankage not too
much of anything other than the grind
this episode and dealing with nether and
all of its shenanigans but we are
definitely making some very heavy
progress in this episode
so all there is left to say is thank you
very much for watching i think you can
see why this episode took such a long
time even if it is just growing my warts
so thank you very much for watching
maybe some of you who know mobs could
tell me
why
these piglens spawning in my nether wart
farm
i don't really understand where they're
spawning
there shouldn't be anywhere for them to
spawn i've got slabs here carpet here
and then there's nether wart everywhere
but every now and again
piglet random
and they hit hard so that's it for me
everyone i hope you enjoyed this episode
thank you very much for watching and i
shall see you in the next one good bye